William Karecky

324 Deerfoot Lane, Brick NJ

(732) 278-0449

WilliamK228@comcast.net

Highly motivated and professional Facility/Project Manager with over fifteen years combined experience in managing projects and building operations. Highly focused with a comprehensive construction and mechanical background to provide the underlying foundation management and building and grounds operations. A confident communicator who exhibits excellent interpersonal skills in working with a wide range of personnel to gain valuable insight and to provide an open line of communication. I am presently looking to join an organization to apply my vast experience, my excellent work ethic and my positive approach to completing tasks to the utmost satisfaction.

- * Project Management Skills
- * Communication Skills
- * Customer Service Oriented
- * Schedule & Budget Mgt.
- * Preventative Maintenance
- * NFPA Life Safety
- * Organizational Skills
- * Vendor & Procurement Mgt.
- * Code Compliance
- * Safety Compliance
- * Problem Solving Skills
- * MEP experience
- * Possess the ability not only to understand the steps associated with Facility/Project management but I'm able to perform most tasks and corrective work as well.
- * Computer literate to adopt existing Project Management or CMMS software already in place.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

UNFI (United Natural Foods) Howell NJ

2015 - Present

Facility Manager - Maintenance Manager

- Managed all aspects of maintenance programs and capital projects (420,000 square feet).
- Managed and supervised maintenance personnel performing preventative and corrective maintenance on overall building functions, systems, grounds and equipment.
- Implemented safety guidelines (OSHA) and continually made general safety improvements.
- Responsible for fire suppressions systems, back-up generators, security, tests and maintenance.
- Prepared, recorded and tracked purchase orders for needed supplies, parts and services.
- Negotiated and managed vendor service contracts and capital improvements bids overseeing the work was performed as per contract specifications.
- Performed and recorded daily inspections of property, equipment and grounds to document needed repairs and/or improvements.
- Collaborated with upper management on maintenance budgets as well as prioritizing capital expenditure improvement projects throughout the facility.

SHORE 2 SHORE ENTERPRISES LLC Brick, NJ PROJECT MANAGER

2005 - 2015

- Meet with clients and/or stakeholders to understand business needs and to define scope.
- Blueprint review while preparing the necessary project and municipal permit documentation.
- Prepare bid packages and held meetings with subcontractors to outline work to be performed.
- Prepare detailed cost and schedule estimates for all phases of the project while adjusting

cost and time parameters associated with each phase of the project.

- Plan and coordinate scheduled work, and visit work sites on a regular basis to gauge contractor performance, quality standards and to confirm all work meets contract requirements.
- Verify site requirements to ensure work being performed meets standard safe work practices and OSHA standards.
- Complete projects within schedule and budget parameters while confirming that all work is satisfactory completed, meet contract requirements and all documents are finalized.

PROJECT MANAGEMENT SAMPLES:

- Ocean County NJ Public Defenders Building Stitch-n-Sew Fabric Warehouse
- Insurance Restoration of Residential/commercial losses Bob Massey Retail Complex

GRMS Associates, Toms River NJ

2002 - 2005

CAPITAL PROJECTS AND BUILDING MAINTENANCE MANAGER:

State Leased Ocean County Public Defenders Building (sub-contracted) The Allen Street Corporate Complex.

- Prepared and managed budgets for work performed, supplies and vendor services.
- Planned, coordinated and conducted day-to-day operations to include general repairs, HVAC, electrical, plumbing, fire suppression, communication, life safety, security, groundskeeping, etc,
- Created work orders and/or performed preventative maintenance.
- Monitored and scheduled existing service contracts for performance.
- Periodic inspections and testing of Life Safety equipment/system to verify they are operable.
- Scheduled State and Local officials for required Life Safety (NFPA) and building inspections.
- Developed and maintained solid relationships with clients and tenants.

BIO-NOMIC RESOURCES Eastern office: Point Pleasant, NJ

Now defunct

INDUSTRIAL MAINTENANCE MECHANIC AND SUPERVISOR (8) years.

- Set-up, operated, repaired and maintained process equipment throughout the US for municipalities and companies such as Exxon, Alcoa, Power Plants, etc.,
- Experienced in electrical (480), PLC's, pneumatics, plumbing, mechanicals, hydraulics, etc,.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATES/TRAINING/SKILLS:

- * Bachelor of Arts, Thomas Edison State University, Trenton, NJ 08608
- * Associate in Computer Science, Excelsior College, Albany, NY 12203
- * HVAC Technician Cert. EPA 608 Universal
- * OSHA 10-hour Training for General Industry
- * Experience with CADD
- * Microsoft Office (Word and Excel).
- * IFMA member.

- * EPA Lead Safety Certificate
- * 360 Insurance Claims Training
- * LEEDS Green Associate course
- * Familiar with Maximo CMMS software
- * Audited and approved by the <u>Project Management Institute</u> (PMI) to take exam to acquire the <u>Project Management Professional (PMP) certification</u>. Estimated exam: August 2017